Defy expectations.
Poor Things is a science fiction, romance, comedy
film directed by Yorgos Lanthimos.
Brought back to life by an unorthodox scientist, a young woman runs off
with a lawyer on a whirlwind adventure across the continents.
Free from the prejudices of her times, she grows steadfast in
her purpose to stand for equality and liberation.
Bella Baxter, played by Emma Stone.
Duncan Wedderburn, played by Mark Ruffalo.
Godwin Baxter, played by Willem Dafoe.
Max McCandles, played by Ramy Youssef.
Alfie Blessington, played by Christopher Abbott.
Toinette, played by Suzy Bemba.
Poor Things is a 2023 film directed by Yorgos Lanthimos and written by
Tony McNamara, based on the 1992 novel by Alasdair Gray.
A co-production between Ireland, the United Kingdom, and the United States, the film stars Emma Stone,
Mark Ruffalo, Willem Dafoe, Ramy Youssef, Christopher Abbott, and Jerrod Carmichael.
It follows Bella Baxter, a young woman in Victorian London who
is brought back to life via brain transplant.
Principal photography took place in Hungary from August to December 2021.
Poor Things premiered at the 80th Venice International Film Festival
on September 1, 2023, and won the Golden Lion there.
The film received critical acclaim and was released theatrically in the United States on December 8,
2023, and in Ireland and the United Kingdom on January 12, 2024, by Searchlight Pictures.
It also became a box office success, grossing over $117 million worldwide on a
budget of $35 million, becoming Lanthimos' highest-grossing film.
Poor Things was named one of the top ten films of 2023 by the National Board of Review and the American Film Institute, and received various accolades, including four wins
at the 96th Academy Awards, two at the 81st Golden Globe Awards, and five at the 77th British Academy Film Awards; Stone won Best Actress at each ceremony.
The film explores themes of ship, london, england,
experiment, paris, france, based on novel or book.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.